Class of 1891 Records, 1866-1997
Smith College Archives
Class of 1891 Records
1866-1997
Smith College. Class of 1891.
RG 80 UUID:d9ae3e54-1870-4389-b1e8-891e8eafdaf9
11 boxes (4 linear ft. and 7 linear inches)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
This collection contains black and white photographs, letters, correspondence, student's journals, publications, manuscripts, newspaper clippings, student's class notes, and memorabilia from the commencement and reunions of the Class of 1891.
The Class of 1891 was the thirteenth graduating class of Smith College.
The Class of 1891 Records contain materials describing the history of the Class of 1891. Types of materials include black and white photographs, letters, correspondence, student's journals, publications, manuscripts, newspaper clippings, student's class notes, and memorabilia from the commencement and reunions of the Class of 1891.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The records are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
History of the Collection
The Class of 1891 Records were created by the students and donated to the College Archives.
- Class of 1891: Baccalaureate Service 1891 (Box 1455, Folder 1)
- Class of 1891: Collation 1891, 1906 (Box 1455, Folder 2)
- Class of 1891: Commencement 1891 (Box 1455, Folder 3)
- Class of 1891: Commencement Music 1891 (Box 1455, Folder 4)
- Class of 1891: Freshman Grind by 1890 (Box 1455, Folder 5)
- Class of 1891: Groups 1886-87, 1889-91 (Box 1455, Folder 6)
- Class of 1891: Ivy Day 1891 (Box 1455, Folder 7)
- Class of 1891: Ivy Day (Photographs) 1891 (Box 1455, Folder 8)
- Class of 1891: Junior Prom 1890 (Box 1455, Folder 9)
- Class of 1891: Class Letters 1898, 1915-17, 1921, 1924, 1945-46, 1948-52, other n.d. (Box 1456, Folder 1)
- Class of 1891: Publications N.d. (Box 1456, Folder 2)
- Class of 1891: Class Secretary's Records 1890s-1950s (Box 1456, Folder 3)
- Class of 1891: Class Supper, History, Prophecies 1891 (Box 1456, Folder 4)
- Class of 1891: Class Photo Book 1891 (Box 1456, Folder 5)
- Class of 1891: Reunions 1911-12, 1916, 1921, 1924-25, 1931, 1941, 1946-48, other n.d. (Box 1456, Folder 6)
- Class of 1891: Reunion Songs 1911, 1921, 1925, 1941, other n.d. (Box 1456, Folder 7)
- Class of 1891: Reunion Photographs 1916, 1936, 1941, 1950, other n.d. (Box 1456, Folder 8)
- Class of 1891: Senior Dramatics 1891 (Box 1456, Folder 9)
- Class of 1891: Senior Dramatics (Photographs) 1891 (Box 1456, Folder 10)
- Class of 1891: Songs 1941, other n.d. (Box 1456, Folder 11)
- Class of 1891: Sophomore Reception 1887 (Box 1456, Folder 12)
- Class of 1891: Sophomore-Senior Reception for 1889 1889 (Box 1456, Folder 13)
- Class of 1891: Class Supper 1891 (Box 1456, Folder 14)
- Class of 1891: Abbot, Florence Hale (Photographs, etc) 1896, 1891, 1918, other n.d. (Box 1457, Folder 1)
- Class of 1891: Aikens, Mary Lydia (Photographs, etc) 1891, other n.d. (Box 1457, Folder 2)
- Class of 1891: Allen, Grace Weston (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1457, Folder 3)
- Class of 1891: Ames, Grace Edith 1888, 1891, other n.d. (Box 1457, Folder 4)
- Class of 1891: Baird, Mary Ellen (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1457, Folder 5)
- Class of 1891: Barbour, Amy Louise (Photographs) (Box 1457, Folder 6)
- Class of 1891: Barri, Alice Hamilton N.d. (Box 1457, Folder 7)
- Class of 1891: Barton, Mary Catherine (Photographs) (Box 1457, Folder 8)
- Class of 1891: Billings, Anna Hunt (Photographs, etc) 1866-1912, 1914, 1941, 1944 (Box 1457, Folder 9)
- Class of 1891: Bixby, Ada Perry (Photographs) (Box 1457, Folder 10)
- Class of 1891: Blanchard, Florence Adelia (Photographs) 1891, 1937, 1947 (Box 1457, Folder 11)
- Class of 1891: Bliss, Helen Rockwell (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1457, Folder 12)
- Class of 1891: Bogue, Stella Margaret (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1457, Folder 13)
- Class of 1891: Booth, Mary Martyn (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1457, Folder 14)
- Class of 1891: Bowman, Blanche Wetherell (Photographs) 1888 (Box 1457, Folder 15)
- Class of 1891: Brown, Harriet Langdon (Photographs, etc) 1918, 1891, other n.d. (Box 1457, Folder 16)
- Class of 1891: Brown, Mary Belle (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1457, Folder 17)
- Class of 1891: Bruce, Grace A. (Box 1457, Folder 18)
- Class of 1891: Cadwallader, Edith Warner (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1457, Folder 19)
- Class of 1891: Cary, Lucia Beecher (Photographs) (Box 1457, Folder 20)
- Class of 1891: Cary, Lucia Beecher (Paper on Charles Lamb) N.d. (Box 1457, Folder 21)
- Class of 1891: Chapman, Carita Atwill (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1457, Folder 22)
- Class of 1891: Churchyard, Mary (Photographs, etc) 1891 (Box 1457, Folder 23)
- Class of 1891: Clark, Edith Ethelyn (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1457, Folder 24)
- Class of 1891: Clute, Alice 1960, other n.d. (Box 1457, Folder 25)
- Class of 1891: Collar, Mary Sibyl 1891 (Box 1457, Folder 26)
- Class of 1891: Comins, Ellen Nellie Maria 1906-08, 1912, other n.d. (Box 1457, Folder 27)
- Class of 1891: De Normandie, Sylvia Yardley 1963 (Box 1457, Folder 28)
- Class of 1891: Dole, Catherine Augusta 1924, other n.d. (Box 1457, Folder 29)
- Class of 1891: Dwight, Bertha W. (Photographs, Letters) 1887-88, 1891, 1953, other n.d. (Box 1457, Folder 30)
- Class of 1891: Dwight, Bertha Woolsey (Lecture Notes, History of French Revolution) 1890 (Box 1457, Folder 31)
- Class of 1891: Dwight, Bertha Woolsey (Lecture Notes, English Literature) 1890, other n.d. (Box 1457, Folder 32)
- Class of 1891: Dwight, Bertha Woolsey (Lecture Notes, American Literature) 1891 (Box 1457, Folder 33)
- Class of 1891: Dwight, Bertha Woolsey (Class Notes, French) N.d. (Box 1457, Folder 34)
- Class of 1891: Fairbanks, Lucy N.d. (Box 1457, Folder 35)
- Class of 1891: Foster, Mary Louise (Box 1457, Folder 36)
- Class of 1891: Franklin, Charlotte G. (Box 1457, Folder 37)
- Class of 1891: Fuller, Susan Gertrude 1912, 1916, 1928, other n.d. (Box 1457, Folder 38)
- Class of 1891: Garland, Olive Rosamond (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1457, Folder 39)
- Class of 1891: Granger, Edith 1904-05, 1919-20, 1925, 1927-28, 1932, 1941, 1957 (Box 1457, Folder 40)
- Class of 1891: Greene, Helen F. (Correspondence, Alumnae Register) 1944-46 (Box 1457, Folder 41)
- Class of 1891: Greene, Helen French (Correspondence and Articles) 1866, 1909, 1925, 1928, 1936, 1947-48, 1952-53 (Box 1457, Folder 42)
- Class of 1891: Greene, Helen French (Photographs) 1885, other n.d. (Box 1457, Folder 43)
- Class of 1891: Greene, Helen French (Reminiscences of Margaret Storrs Grierson, '22) 1980 (Box 1457, Folder 44)
- Class of 1891: Greene, Helen French (Will) 1948 (Box 1457, Folder 45)
- Class of 1891: Gulliver, Eunice Henrietta (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1457, Folder 46)
- Class of 1891: Gutmann, Gertrude Louise (Box 1457, Folder 47)
- Class of 1891: Hastings, Dora Loomis 1902 (Box 1458, Folder 1)
- Class of 1891: Hewitt, Helen Witter (Photographs) 1890, other n.d. (Box 1458, Folder 2)
- Class of 1891: Hill, Ellen Elisabeth (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1458, Folder 3)
- Class of 1891: Hoysradt, Jessie (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1458, Folder 4)
- Class of 1891: Husted, Mary Irving (Photographs) (Box 1458, Folder 5)
- Class of 1891: Keyes, Bertha Anna (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1458, Folder 6)
- Class of 1891: Lamprey, Eva Blanche (Photographs) 1888, 1890, other n.d. (Box 1458, Folder 7)
- Class of 1891: Lang, Mary Susan (Photographs, etc) 1887-88, 1890, 1938, 1961, 1964, 1980, other n.d. (Box 1458, Folder 8)
- Class of 1891: Lauriat, Susette Foster (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1458, Folder 9)
- Class of 1891: Lord, Helen Augusta (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1458, Folder 10)
- Class of 1891: Mead, Katharine Lois (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1458, Folder 11)
- Class of 1891: North, Georgia Lincoln (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1458, Folder 12)
- Class of 1891: Olmsted, Frances Elizabeth (Photographs) 1889 (Box 1458, Folder 13)
- Class of 1891: Ordway, Fanny Blanche (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1458, Folder 14)
- Class of 1891: Osgood, Alice Florella (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1458, Folder 15)
- Class of 1891: Paul, Florence Helen (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1458, Folder 16)
- Class of 1891: Peck, Carolyn (Photographs, etc) 1890-91, 1913, 1947, other n.d. (Box 1458, Folder 17)
- Class of 1891: Peirce, Helen (Photographs) 1891, other n.d. (Box 1458, Folder 18)
- Class of 1891: Phillips, Mary Louise (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1458, Folder 19)
- Class of 1891: Platt, Eloise Clara (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1458, Folder 20)
- Class of 1891: Porter, Jeanne P. (Box 1458, Folder 21)
- Class of 1891: Puffer, Ethel Dench (Box 1458, Folder 22)
- Class of 1891: Rand, Grace 1891 (Box 1458, Folder 23)
- Class of 1891: Raymond, Mary Elizabeth 1891, 1932, 1937, 1950, 1996-97 (Box 1458, Folder 24)
- Class of 1891: Rice, Helen Rebecca (Photographs) 1891, other n.d. (Box 1458, Folder 25)
- Class of 1891: Robinson, Annie Florence (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1458, Folder 26)
- Class of 1891: Rogerson, Frances Rice (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1458, Folder 27)
- Class of 1891: Sabin, Mary Sophia (Photographs, etc) 1891, 1961, other n.d. (Box 1458, Folder 28)
- Class of 1891: Sawin, Laura Etta 1910 (Box 1458, Folder 29)
- Class of 1891: Severens, Mabel (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1458, Folder 30)
- Class of 1891: Sherman, Ellen Burns (Photographs) (Box 1458, Folder 31)
- Class of 1891: Sherwood, Alice (Photographs, Letters) 1890, 1921, other n.d. (Box 1458, Folder 32)
- Class of 1891: Simmons, Adeline Gertrude (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1458, Folder 33)
- Class of 1891: Skinner, Lilian 1907, 1912-13, 1915, 1918, 1922, 1924-27, 1931 (Box 1458, Folder 34)
- Class of 1891: Slaght, Ethelwyn Rebecca 1893-94, 1897, other n.d. (Box 1458, Folder 35)
- Class of 1891: Smith, May Manning (Photographs) 1891 (Box 1458, Folder 36)
- Class of 1891: Sterne, Alice Louie 1910 (Box 1458, Folder 37)
- Class of 1891: Stetson, Jennie (Photographs, etc) 1891, 1898, other n.d. (Box 1458, Folder 38)
- Class of 1891: Taylor, Caro Cushing 1891-92? (Box 1458, Folder 39)
- Class of 1891: Trowbridge, Cornelia Rogers (Photographs) 1901 (Box 1458, Folder 40)
- Class of 1891: Waite, Constance Eliza 1952 (Box 1458, Folder 41)
- Class of 1891: Wallace, Janet Monroe (Box 1458, Folder 42)
- Class of 1891: Whitehill, Clara Agnes (Photographs, etc) 1960, other n.d. (Box 1458, Folder 43)
- Class of 1891: Wilder, Matilda Sewell (Photographs) N.d. (Box 1458, Folder 44)
- Class of 1891: Williams, Elizabeth Sprague (Photographs, etc) 1890, 1912, 1914, 1922-23, 1970, other n.d. (Box 1458, Folder 45)
- Class of 1891: Williams, Elizabeth Sprague 1914, other n.d. (Box 1458, Folder 46)
- Class of 1891: Wilson, Mary Elizabeth (Photographs, etc) N.d. (Box 1458, Folder 47)
- Class of 1891: Wood, Mabel (Photographs, etc) 1891, 1898, 1936, 1949, 1951, other n.d. (Box 1458, Folder 48)
- Class of 1891: Sherman, Ellen (Miscellaneous) 1941, other n.d. (Box 1459, Folder 1)
- Class of 1891: Sherman, Ellen (Anthology, Poems) 1916-17, other n.d. (Box 1459, Folder 2)
- Class of 1891: Sherman, Ellen (Manuscripts, etc) 1914, 1945, other n.d. (Box 1459)
- Class of 1891: Sherman, Ellen (Manuscripts) N.d. (Box 1460)
- Class of 1891: Sherman, Ellen (Manuscripts) 1953, other n.d. (Box 1461)
- Class of 1891: Sherman, Ellen (Manuscripts) 1899, 1902, 1906, 1908-09, 1912, 1914-19, 1921-24, 1926-27, 1935-36, 1938-46 (Box 1462)
- Class of 1891: Wallace, Janet Monroe (Letters) 1887-1890, other n.d. (Box 1463)
- Class of 1891: Wallace, Janet Monroe (Letters) 1890-91, 1895 (Box 1464)
- Class of 1891: Wallace, Janet Monroe (Student papers, Journal, Miscellaneous) 1881-89, 1891, 1895, 1915-16, 1925-26, 1929-30, 1933-38, 1940-42, 1944-48, 1978, other n.d. (Box 1465)